Jonas Eduardsen

Curriculum Vitae

Fibigerstræde 11 9220 Aalborg East Denmark ☎ +45 9940 8364 ⊠ jse@business.aau.dk



Summary

I am an Associate Prof. of International Business and Marketing in the Department of Business and Management at Aalborg University (Denmark), where I have been a faculty member since 2016. I completed my PhD in International Business at Aalborg University, where I focused on how decision-makers in small- and medium-sized firms perceive risk associated with doing business in foreign markets and the coping mechanisms used for dealing with these risks.

My current research interests' centres on the internationalisation of firms, with a specific focus on explaining firm's internationalisation behaviours, the internationalization-performance relationship, and providing suggestions to improve internationalisation performance. My vision is to become a leading expert in SME internationalisation and an important contributor of innovative and relevant research that can help SMEs seeking to expand their business abroad and policy-makers who wish to support and facilitate SME internationalisation.

I am greatly inspired by "problem-based learning" as a teaching philosophy. I believe that students learn best when applying theory and research-based knowledge in their work with an authentic problem. I believe that having an authentic problem as the starting point directing the student's learning process, facilitates deep learning and strengthen the students' skills as regards to problem identification and formulation, complex problem solving, critical thinking, and creativity. All skills that are crucial in their future careers.

Education

2012–2016 Ph.D. in International Business, Aalborg University, Aalborg.

Title: Risk perception and risk accommodation in the internationalisation process: A qualitative study of decision-makers in Danish SMEs

2009–2011 MSc. International Business Economics, Aalborg University, Aalborg.

2007–2009 BSc. Economics and Business Administration, Aalborg University, Aalborg.

2005–2007 AP. Financial Management, University College of Northern Jutland, Aalborg.

Employment history

2020- Associate Professor, Aalborg University, Aalborg University Business School.

2016-2020 Assistant Professor, Aalborg University, Department of Business and Management.

2012-2012 Ph.D. Fellow, Aalborg University, Department of Business and Management.

2011-2012 Research Assistant, Aalborg University, Department of Business and Management.

Teaching experience

- 2016– **Marketing Research**, *BSc. Economics and Business Administration*, 4th semester, Department of Business and Management, Aalborg University.
- 2012– **Business research methods**, *MSc. International Business Economics and MSc. International Marketing*, 7th semester, Department of Business and Management, Aalborg University.
- 2012– **E-Business**, *MSc. International Business Economics and MSc. International Marketing*, 7th semester, Department of Business and Management, Aalborg University.
- 2012- **Method and research design**, *MSc. Innovation Management*, 7th semester, Sino-Danish Center, China.
- 2019– **Export Marketing**, *MSc. International Marketing*, 8th Semester, Department of Business and Management, Aalborg University.

Administrative experience

- 2020- **Program Coordinator**, *MSc. International Business*, Aalborg University, Department of Business and Management.
- 2020- **Elected Member of Department Council**, Aalborg University, Aalborg University Business School.
- 2019-2020 **Program Coordinator**, *MSc. International Marketing*, Aalborg University, Department of Business and Management.
- 2019-2020 **Member of Study Board**, *BSc. Economics and Business Administration*, Aalborg University, Department of Business and Management.
- 2019-2020 **Steering Committee**, Det Nordjyske Virksomhedspanel.

Supervision

MSc. International Business Economics.

Project supervision, including supervision of semester projects and Master theses, where I advise students by commenting on the students' project work, provide constructive criticism and provide ideas for methods, theories etc.

MSc. International Marketing.

Project supervision, including supervision of semester projects and Master theses, where I advise students by commenting on the students' project work, provide constructive criticism and provide ideas for methods, theories etc.

MSc. Innovation Management.

Project supervision of semester projects, where I advise students by commenting on the students' project work, provide constructive criticism and provide ideas for methods, theories etc.

BSc. Economics and Business Administration.

Project supervision of Bachelor theses, where I advise students by commenting on the students' project work, provide constructive criticism and provide ideas for methods, theories etc.

Current Research Projects

2019-2021 **COGINT: Cognition and Internationalisation**.

This project explores how cognitive processes, including managerial judgement, reasoning and sense-making, influence and shape managerial decision-making related to internationalisation and are crucial in explaining observed heterogeneity in internationalisation strategies and performance. This research project is a collaboration between AAU, University of Vigo, and Catolica Porto Business School.

2015-2020 SINET: SMEs Internationalisation Network.

The project explores the role of decision-making, innovation and Network attachments in the internationalisation of SMEs, Thirty companies in three different sectors (biotech, IT and garments) in each one of the countries participating (Denmark, United Kingdom, Poland, Egypt, UAE, India, China) in the study have been studied through semi-structured interviews.

2018-2021 Cross-border E-commerce and SME internationalisation.

This projects explores the impact of e-commerce of firm internationalisation and the main drivers of online export performance, including how individual-, firm- and country-level factors influence this impact. In addition, the project explores the main drivers of online export performance.

2019-2020 ENHANCE: Enhancing Value Creation and Value Capture through Business Model Configuration.

The project aims to develop a Nordic research platform on the interface between small and mediumsized enterprises' business models, entrepreneurship and internationalisation with an ecosystem view.